<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Utopia</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Utopia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/about/</guid>
      <description>About MeHi, my name is Kaiwen Teoh but you can just call me Kalvin. I’m a second-year student who is currently studying Statistical Computing and Operations Research at University Tunku Abdul Rahman in Perak, Malaysia. I don’t cook but I do like carbonara spaghetti, ikan bakar, almond dessert, and many more.

BlogThis blog is about statistics, operations research, data analysis and its visualization while using mainly R, and a little bit of my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create correlation network plot in a quick way</title>
      <link>/post/create-a-correlation-network-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/create-a-correlation-network-plot/</guid>
      <description>Corrr package
From my previous post, I did mention about the use of network plot from ‘corrr’ package in visualizing correlation matrices. So, for this time, I’m going to share with you on how to create your own correlation network plot by using ‘corrr’ package in a quick way and also how do we actually interpret it in short.

Installation
Download and install the ‘corrr’ and ‘magrittr’ R packages from CRAN for the first time before we can make use of the functions from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correlation and Covariance</title>
      <link>/post/correlation-and-covariance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/correlation-and-covariance/</guid>
      <description>RECIPEIntro to Correlation Intro to Covariance Difference between Correlation and Covariance Hypothesis test about a correlation, \(\rho\) Testing difference between two correlation coefficients Visualizing correlationScatter plot Visualizing correlation matricesSymbolic Number Coding
Scatter Plot Matrix
Network Plot
Correlogram
Correlation
What?
A correlation, r is a statistical way that describes the degree of relationship between two quantitative variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporary Post</title>
      <link>/project/temporary-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/temporary-post/</guid>
      <description>Still working on it, be right back!

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A hint on how to read World Bank data into R</title>
      <link>/post/read-world-bank-data-into-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/read-world-bank-data-into-r/</guid>
      <description>World Bank is an ideal place for us to access global development data. We can always search suitable open data by relevant keyword and download it in any format we prefer (CSV, XML, EXCEL). However, if you are the guy who prefers to wrangle data with R, then there is another option for you to deal with it instead of download open data from World Bank into your pc and import into R manually by using read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis testing</title>
      <link>/post/hypothesis-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hypothesis-testing/</guid>
      <description>MENU*Introduction

*Hypothesis test about a population mean, \(\mu\)

*Hypothesis test about a population proportion, p


Introduction
A hypothesis test is a standard procedure for testing a claim about a property of a population. A formal hypothesis test has few components which includes null hypothesis, alternative hypothesis, test statistics, p-value, tail of test, type I and type II error.

A population parameter is a statistical measure that for a given population is fixed and can be used in the description of that population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data wrangling with dplyr, tidyr and gsub()</title>
      <link>/post/data-wrangling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-wrangling/</guid>
      <description>During my semester one in year two, I was given the opportunity to take part in the annual IBM Watson Analytics competition. Overall, it was a pleasant experience and I did learn a lot of things from it. One of them was how to make use of R in wrangling datasets. It was my first time to join and words couldn’t explain my feelings and gratitude towards my academic advisor for her approach, guidance and patience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>